Francis Gevrier Guittard papers, Inclusive: 1811-1960, undated, Bulk: 1900-1940
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
- Photographic Materials, 1893-1952, undated; 6
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 4: WWI: Railway Street and the New Church in the Fair, Nizhini Novgorod, Russia. (2 of 14), undated (Box 19, Folder 51)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 4: WWI: The Great Bell Market at the Fair, Nizhini Novgorod, Russia. (3 of 14), undated (Box 19, Folder 52)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 4: WWI: Nizhini Novgorod Floating Bridge, River Oka, Russia. (4 of 14), undated (Box 19, Folder 53)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 4: WWI: The Fair, Nizhini Novgorod, from the City, Russia. (5 of 14), undated (Box 19, Folder 54)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 4: WWI: The Krestchatik, the Principal Street of Kiev [EL] of the Famous Old Cities of Russia. (6 of 14), undated (Box 19, Folder 55)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 4: WWI: The Cloth Market at the Fair, Nizhini Novgorod, Russia. (7 of 14), undated (Box 19, Folder 56)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 4: WWI: The Principal Street in the Fair, Nizhini Novgorod, Russia. (8 of 14), undated (Box 19, Folder 57)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 4: WWI: The Nikolskaja Gate to the Kitai Gorod, Kremlin, Moscow. (9 of 14), undated (Box 19, Folder 58)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 4: WWI: In the Great Vegetable Market of Moscow, Russia. (10 of 14), undated (Box 19, Folder 59)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 4: WWI: Russian PeasantsDLCrude Method of Crushing Corn by Hand. (11 of 14), undated (Box 19, Folder 60)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 4: WWI: Quaint Dairy Maids Delivering Milk in Earthenware Jars Suspended on Poles, Kiev, Russia. (12 of 14), undated (Box 19, Folder 61)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 4: WWI: The Nicholas Suspension Bridge over the Dneiper, Russia. (13 of 14), undated (Box 19, Folder 62)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 4: WWI: Cattle in a Russian Village Being Driven to the Water for Benediction. (14 of 14), undated (Box 19, Folder 63)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 5: WWI: Canton Bridge. (1 of 16), undated (Box 19, Folder 64)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 5: WWI: Sarajevo from the Porch of New Town Hall, Bosnia, Austria-Hungary. (2 of 16), undated (Box 19, Folder 65)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 5: WWI: Senate and the Academy on the Vasili Island, St. Petersburg, Russia. (3 of 16), undated (Box 19, Folder 66)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 5: WWI: German Scout Watching in Anticipation of a Russian Attack on the Trenches. (4 of 16), undated (Box 19, Folder 67)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 5: WWI: An Old Finland Fisherman. (5 of 16), undated (Box 19, Folder 68)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 5: WWI: St. Isaac’s Cathedral, St. Petersburg, Russia. (6 of 16), undated (Box 19, Folder 69)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 5: WWI: The Imperial Winter Palace, St. Petersburg, Russia. (7 of 16), undated (Box 19, Folder 70)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 5: WWI: [Map of the Italian Campaign] (8 of 16), undated (Box 19, Folder 71)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 5: WWI: The Great Saturday Market in Helsingfors, Finland. (9 of 16), undated (Box 19, Folder 72)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 5: WWI: Norra Esplanadgatan, the Principal Street in Helsingfors, Finland. (10 of 16), undated (Box 19, Folder 73)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 5: WWI: Fish Wives of FinlandDLA Busy Scene on the Quay. (11 of 16), undated (Box 19, Folder 74)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 5: WWI: The Alexander Column, St. Petersburg, Russia. (12 of 16), undated (Box 19, Folder 75)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 5: WWI: The Nevski Prospekt, St. Petersburg, Russia. (13 of 16), undated (Box 19, Folder 76)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 5: WWI: Nevski Prospekt, Looking East, Showing Tower of City Hall, St. Petersburg, Russia. (14 of 16), undated (Box 19, Folder 77)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 5: WWI: The Fountain Terrace before the Palace of Peterof, St. Petersburg, Russia. (15 of 16), undated (Box 19, Folder 78)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 5: WWI: Quarters for the German Horses Used in Russian Poland, Eastern Zone of the European War. (16 of 16), undated (Box 19, Folder 79)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 6: WWI: Ready to Charge the Russian Lines. (1 of 17), undated (Box 19, Folder 80)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 6: WWI: Terraced Trenches in Quick Sand, Built by German Soldiers in a Pine Forest on the Eastern Front. (2 of 17), undated (Box 19, Folder 81)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 6: WWI: Mammoth Naval Gun Used by Russians in Land Defense of Port Arthur. (3 of 17), undated (Box 19, Folder 82)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 6: WWI: The Long Bridge Across Vistula River, Warsaw, Russia, Poland. (4 of 17), undated (Box 19, Folder 83)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 6: WWI: Day Guard Duty in the German Trenches on the Eastern Front. (5 of 17), undated (Box 19, Folder 84)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 6: WWI: Plowing with a Primitive Native PlowDLHow the Russian Peasant Tills His Leased Fields. (6 of 17), undated (Box 19, Folder 85)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 6: WWI: [Map of Western Campaign] (7 of 17), undated (Box 19, Folder 86)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 6: WWI: A Polish Market in War Time. (8 of 17), undated (Box 19, Folder 87)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 6: WWI: German Look-Out Guard in the Loft of a Wrecked Russian Barn. (9 of 17), undated (Box 19, Folder 88)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 6: WWI: German Soldiers Occupying Trenches on Captured Russian Lands. (10 of 17), undated (Box 19, Folder 89)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 6: WWI: A Pioneer of the Kaiser’s Forests Shattered into Toothpicks by a Shell from the Russian Lines. (11 of 17), undated (Box 19, Folder 90)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 6: WWI: German Soldiers’ Graves and Crude Monument for Men Who Fell on the Eastern Battle Lines. (12 of 17), undated (Box 19, Folder 91)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 6: WWI: Russian Wounded in the Hospital. (13 of 17), undated (Box 19, Folder 92)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 6: WWI: Spoils of War Captured in the Russian Retreat in the East. (14 of 17), undated (Box 19, Folder 93)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 6: WWI: Market Day in the Crowded Jewish Quarters, Warsaw, Poland. (15 of 17), undated (Box 19, Folder 94)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 6: WWI: Kaiser Wilhelm’s Soldiers Studying the Mechanics of a Captured Russian Machine Gun. (16 of 17), undated (Box 19, Folder 95)
  - Magic Lantern Slides: Box 6: WWI: Russian Officers as Prisoners. (17 of 17), undated (Box 19, Folder 96)
  - Baylor University Group Photograph, 1908 December 14 (Folder 3)
  - Print: Athens, Greece: Acropolis, undated (Box [1068] OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Print: Rome, Italy: Arch of Titus, undated (Box [1068] OVZ, Folder 6)
  - Print: Venice, Italy: Piazza San Marco, undated (Box [1068] OVZ, Folder 7)
  - Album: Acquaintances and Students, undated (Box 26 OVZ, Folder 1)
- Artifacts, 1885-1915, undated; 7
  The following series contains personal items belonging to Francis Guittard including a political pin, various ribbons, and a pair of eyeglasses. The materials are in average condition.
  - Pin: Franklin Roosevelt and John Garner, undated (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Ribbons: Baylor University, 1907-1915, undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Ribbons: General, 1885-1896, undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Eyeglasses, undated (Box [1071], Folder 5)
- Certificates, 1884-1931; 8
  The following series contains certificates and awards collected by the Guittard family. Prominent items include Francis Joseph Guittard's medical certificates, Francis Gevrier Guittard's diplomas from the University of Chicago, and the wedding certificate for Guittard's marriage to Mamie Welhausen. The materials are in good condition.
  - General: Francis Gevrier Guittard, 1884-1902 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - General: Francis Gevrier Guittard, 1924-1949 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - General: Francis Joseph Guittard: Medical, 1854-1868 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - General: Josephine Glenn Guittard, 1910-1924 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Diploma: Leland Stanford Junior University: Doctor of Philosophy: Francis Gevrier Guittard, 1931 April 3 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Plaque: Memorial: Lydia M. Guittard, circa 1889 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Diploma: Francis Gevrier Guittard, 1889-1902 (Box [1068] OVZ, Folder 8)
  - Marriage: Francis Gevrier Guittard and Mamie Welhausen, 1906 December 24 (Box [1068] OVZ, Folder 9)
- Scrapbooks, 1920-1937; 9
  The following series contains two scrapbooks compiled by the Guittards. Scrapbook One contains brochures, clippings, postcards, and photographs pertaining to Baylor University, Pat Neff, and the Guittard family. Scrapbook Two consists of materials gathered from a family vacation taken in 1937. The materials are in good condition.
  - Guittard Family, 1920-1937 (Box 26 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Family Vacation: Guittards, 1937 (Box [1070] OVZ, Folder 1)
- Maps, 1911-1941, undated; 10
  The following series contains maps collected by Francis Guittard. The foci of these maps range in diversity from individual states to the South China Sea. The materials are in good condition.
  - Enlargement: “Strategy of the South China Sea”: Time, 1941 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Info-Map: Gulf: Alabama, undated (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Info-Map: Gulf: Louisiana, undated (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Info-Map: Gulf: Ohio, undated (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Info-Map: Gulf: Texas, undated (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Plat Map: Hat Box Field: Muskogee, Oklahoma, 1929 November 4 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Pocket Map: Rand-McNally: Philippine Islands, 1911 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Road Map: Conoco: United States, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Road Map: Gulf: United States, 1931 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Road Map: West Virginia, 1937 July (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Site Map: Camp MacArthur, undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Tourist Map: Chattanooga, Tennessee, undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Tourist Map: Niagara Falls, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Classroom Records, 1897-1949, undated; 11
  The following series contains attendance books, grade books, and other classroom materials created by Dr. Francis Gevrier Guittard. Due to privacy laws, these materials could be restricted to the public. Please see an archivist for details. The materials are in good condition.
  - Attendance Book, 1915-1916 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Attendance Book, 1916-1917 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Attendance Book, 1917-1919 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Attendance Book, 1920-1921 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Attendance Book, 1921-1923 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Attendance Book, 1939-1940 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Attendance Book, 1940-1941 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Attendance Book, 1941-1943 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Attendance Book, 1942-1944 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Attendance Book, 1944-1946 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Attendance Book, 1945-1947 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Attendance Book, 1946-1947 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Attendance Book (1 of 2), 1947-1948 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Attendance Book (2 of 2), 1947-1948 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Attendance Book, 1948-1949 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Grade Book, 1902, 1908 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Grade Book, 1903 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Grade Book, 1903, 1904 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Grade Book, 1905-1906 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Grade Book, 1906 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Grade Book, 1907-1909 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Grade Book, 1908-1909 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Grade Book, 1909 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Grade Book, 1910 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Grade Book, 1910-1911 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Grade Book, 1911-1912 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Grade Book, 1913-1914 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Grade Book, 1914-1916 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Grade Book, 1915-1916 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Grade Book, 1916-1917 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Grade Book, 1917-1919 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Grade Book, 1919-1921 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Grade Book, 1921-1923 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Grade Book, 1939-1940 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Grade Book, 1940-1941 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Grade Book, 1941-1943 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Grade Book, 1942-1944 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Grade Book, 1944-1946 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Grade Book, 1945-1947 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Grade Book, 1946-1947 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Grade Book (1 of 2), 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Grade Book (2 of 2), 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Grade Book, 1948-1949 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Grade Book, undated (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Printed Materials: General, 1922, undated (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Printed Materials: University of Chicago, 1897-1904 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Reports: GRE Scores: Baylor University Seniors, undated (Box 23, Folder 15)